片名：公主新娘
嗨，宝贝
Hi, honey.
嗨，妈妈
Hi, Mom.
好点了吗？
You feeling any better?
好点了
A little bit.
知道吗？
Guess what.
什么？
What?
爷爷来了
Grandfather's here.
妈妈 你就不能告诉他我病了吗？
Mom, can't you tell him that I'm sick?
你病了.所以他来了
You're sick. That's why he's here.
他会捏我的脸的
He'll pinch my cheek.
我不喜欢
I hate that.
或许他不会呢
Maybe he won't.
小病人怎样了？
How's the sickie?
我让你们一起聊吧
I'll leave you two pals alone.
我给了带了 一份特别的礼物
I brought you a special present.
-什么啊？ -拆开它
- What is it? - Open it up.
-一本书？ -对
- A book? - That's right.
当我像你这么大时 电视就叫做书
When I was your age, television was called books.
这是一本特别的书
This is a special book.
过去当我病的时候 我的父亲就会给我读了
It was the book my father used to read to me when I was sick...
我过去也给你父亲读过
and I used to read it to your father.
今天我要给你读
Today I'm going to read it to you.
里面有什么体育的内容吗？
Does it got any sports in it?
你在开玩笑啊？
Are you kidding?
剑术，搏击，拷问，报仇…
Fencing, fighting, torture, revenge...
巨人，怪物，追捕…
giants, monsters, chases...
逃跑，真爱，奇迹
escapes, true love, miracles.
听起来不赖
That doesn't sound too bad.
我会试着不睡着的
I'll try and stay awake.
谢谢，那就太好了
Thank you very much. That's very nice of you.
你的信任投票是无法抵挡的
Your vote of confidence is overwhelming.
好的
All right.
“公主新娘”
''The Princess Bride...
“作者是摩根斯特尼”
''by S. Morgenstern.
“第一章”
''Chapter One.
布特卡普是在一个 叫弗罗林的村庄里…
''Buttercup was raised on a small farm...
“一个农场长大的”
''in the country of Florin.
“她最喜欢的消遣 就是骑着她的马…”
''Her favorite pastimes were riding her horse...
“打扰在那儿 工作的农场小伙”
''and tormenting the farm boy that worked there.
“他的名字叫维斯特雷 但她从来都不这么称呼他”
''His name was Westley, but she never called him that.''
这难道不是 一个好的开头吗？
Isn't that a wonderful beginning?
是的，很好
Yeah, it's really good.
“布特卡普觉得 最快乐的是…”
''Nothing gave Buttercup as much pleasure...
“吩咐维斯特雷干这干那”
as ordering Westley around.''
农场小伙 擦一下我的马鞍
Farm boy, polish my horse's saddle.
早晨时我要它光亮 到能照出我的脸
I want to see my face shining in it by morning.
遵你所愿
As you wish.
“遵你所愿” 几乎就是他对她的说话内容
''As you wish'' was all he ever said to her.
农场小伙，把这些都装满水
Farm boy, fill these with water.
拜托
Please.
遵你所愿
As you wish.
那天她很惊讶的发现…
That day she was amazed to discover...
当他说 “遵你所愿”时…
that when he was saying, ''As you wish''...
他的意思是，“我爱你”
what he meant was, ''I love you.''
更令人惊讶的 是她意识到….
Even more amazing was the day she realized...
自己也爱上了他
she truly loved him back.
农场小伙
Farm boy.
装一壶水
Fetch me that pitcher.
遵你所愿
As you wish.
等等，等等
Hold it, hold it.
这是什么？ 你想哄我啊？
What is this? Are you trying to trick me?
哪里有体育的内容？
And where's the sports?
这不就是 一本说接吻的书吗？
Is this a kissing book?
等一下，别急
Wait. Just wait.
什么时候才有好内容出现？
When does it get good?
穿上你的衣服，听我读
Keep your shirt on and let me read.
“维斯特雷没钱结婚…”
''Westley had no money for marriage...
“所以他简单收拾了 一下行装离开了农场…”
''so he packed his few belongings and left the farm...
“跨越大海去碰碰运气”
''to seek his fortune across the sea.''
那对布特卡普来说是 一个很伤感的时刻
It was a very emotional time for Buttercup.
我不相信这个！
I don't believe this!
我担心我再也见不到你了
I fear I'll never see you again.
当然你会见到我的
Of course you will.
如果你出了什么事呢？
What if something happens to you?
听着…
Hear this now...
我总是会出现在你身边的
I will always come for you.
但你怎么能这么肯定？
But how can you be sure?
这就是真爱
This is true love.
你认为这每天都会发生吗？
Do you think this happens every day?
维斯特雷没有到达目的地
Westley didn't reach his destination.
他的船受到可怕的 罗伯茨海盗的袭击
His ship was attacked by the Dread Pirate Roberts...
他们从来都不会 让俘虏活命的
who never left captives alive.
当布特卡普得知 维斯特雷被杀害…
When Buttercup got the news that Westley was murdered...
被海盗杀害精采的
Murdered by pirates is good!
她就跑进自己的 房间把门关上…
She went into her room and shut the door...
几天几夜不食不眠
and for days she neither slept nor ate.
我再也不会恋爱了
I will never love again.
五年后 弗罗林城的广场…
Five years later, the main square of Florin City...
挤满了人群在 听王子胡姆普丁克…
was filled as never before to hear the announcement...
宣布他的新娘子
of the great Prince Humperdinck's bride-to-be.
我的人民
My people...
从现在开始的 一个月里…
a month from now...
我们的国家将 举行500周年庆典
our country will have its 500th anniversary.
日落后 我将娶一位女士…
On that sundown, I shall marry a lady...
她曾经就像 你们一样平常…
who was once a commoner like yourselves...
但或许你们现在 将不会再觉得她平常了
but perhaps you will not find her common now.
你们想见见她吗？
Would you like to meet her?
我的人民 公主布特卡普！
My people, the princess Buttercup!
布特卡普的空虚 侵袭着她
Buttercup's emptiness consumed her.
虽然国家的法律 给了胡姆普丁克…
Although the law of the land gave Humperdinck...
选择新娘的权力…
the right to choose his bride...
但她并不爱他
she did not love him.
尽管胡姆普丁克认为…
Despite Humperdinck's reassurance: : :
她会慢慢爱上他…
That she would grow to love him...
而她唯一找到的乐趣 是每天都骑马
the only joy she found was in her daily ride.
请问一下，女士？
A word, my lady?
我们只是穷困潦倒 迷了路的马戏团演员
We are but poor, lost circus performers.
附近有村落吗？
Is there a village nearby?
附近什么也没有 几公里内什么都没有
There is nothing nearby, not for miles.
那么就没人会听见你叫了
Then there will be no one to hear you scream.
你在撕什么？
What is that you're ripping?
这是军队长官 基尔德制服的物品
It's fabric from the uniform of an army officer of Guilder.
谁是基尔德？
Who's Guilder?
海对面的国家 和弗罗林有不共戴天之仇
The country across the sea, the sworn enemy of Florin.
走！
Go!
一旦这马到了古堡…
Once the horse reaches the castle...
这物品会让王子怀疑…
the fabric will make the prince suspect...
基尔德人绑架了他的爱人
that the Guilderians have abducted his love.
当他发现她的尸体 在基尔德的边疆内…
When he finds her body dead on the Guilder frontier...
他的怀疑就会被确认
his suspicions will be totally confirmed.
你从没说过要杀人
You never said anything about killing anyone.
我雇你来是协助 我挑起一场战争
I've hired you to help me start a war.
这是具有悠久 而光荣的传统里的….
It's a prestigious line of work...
一份有声望的工作
with a long and glorious tradition.
我只是认为杀害一位 无辜女士是不对的
I just don't think it's right, killing an innocent girl.
是我疯了，还是“想”这个词 从你的嘴唇里溜了出来
Am I going mad, or did the word ''think'' escape your lips?
雇你不是因为 要用你的脑子…
You were not hired for your brains...
你这个河马般的巨无霸
you hippopotamic land mass!
我同意菲兹克
I agree with Fezzik.
酒鬼说话了
The sot has spoken!
她有什么事 完全不关你的事
What happens to her is not truly your concern!
我会杀了她的
I will kill her!
记住这点 永远不要忘记这点
And remember this, never forget this...
当我找到你时 你还是一个流着口水的醉鬼…
When I found you, you were so slobbering drunk...
你可买不起白兰地
you couldn't buy brandy!
而你，无依无靠 蠢笨如猪…
And you... friendless, brainless...
无助，绝望！
helpless, hopeless!
你是不是要我把 你送回到格陵岛…
Do you want me to send you back to where you were...
当一个失业流民？
unemployed in Greenland?
那维兹尼 他老是大惊小怪…
That Vizzini, he can... fuss.
大惊小怪…
Fuss, fuss...
我想他喜欢对 我们大呼小叫
I think he like to scream... at us.
或许他并没恶意
Probably he means no... harm.
他真的一点个人 魅力都没有
He's really very short on... charm.
你在押韵方面有天赋
You have a great gift for rhyme.
对，有时候是
Yes, yes, some of the time.
够了
Enough of that!
菲兹克，前面有礁石吗？
Fezzik, are there rocks ahead?
如果有的话 我们都得死
If there are, we'll all be dead.
不要再押韵了 我是说真的！
No more rhymes, now. I mean it!
谁要花生的？
Anybody want a peanut?
我们会在黎明时刻 到达悬崖
We'll reach the cliffs by dawn.
你为什么要这样做？
Why are you doing that?
确保没人跟踪我们啊
Making sure nobody's following us.
那真的是难以置信
That would be inconceivable.
不管你们怎么想…
Despite what you think...
你们都会被逮住 那时候…
you will be caught, and when you are...
王子就会把 你们都绞死的
the prince will see you all hanged.
船上所有人的 脖子都会，殿下…
Of all the necks on this boat, Highness...
而你要担心的 其中一个是你自己的
the one you should be worrying about is your own.
不要这样做了！
Stop doing that!
我们可以放松一下. 几乎要结束了
We can all relax. It's almost over.
你确定没人跟踪我们吗？
You are sure nobody's following us?
正如我对你所说的 那是完完全全，彻彻底底…
As I told you, it would be absolutely, totally...
不可想像的！
and in all other ways inconceivable!
没有任何基尔德的 人知道我们在干什么…
No one in Guilder knows what we've done...
也没有任何弗罗林的人 能这么快到达那儿
and no one in Florin could have gotten here so fast.
出于好奇心 你为什么要问？
Out of curiosity, why do you ask?
我碰巧往后看 有些东西在那儿
I happened to look behind us, and something is there.
什么？
What?
或许是当地的渔民…
Probably some local fisherman...
晚上出来出海兜风而已
out for a pleasure cruise at night...
就在鳗鱼滋生的水域
through eel-infested waters.
什么？
What?
跳下去！捉她！
Go in! Get after her!
我不会游泳
I don't swim.
我只会狗爬式
I only dog-paddle.
向左拐
Veer left!
左！
Left!
你知道那是什么 声音吗，殿下？
Do you know what that sound is, Highness?
那是鳗鱼的尖叫声
Those are the shrieking eels.
如果你不相信我的话 就等着瞧
If you don't believe me, just wait.
会越来越大声的…
They always grow louder...
特别是当它们 要享用新鲜的人肉时
when they're about to feed on human flesh.
如果你现在游回来…
If you swim back now...
我保证不会伤害你
I promise no harm will come to you.
但我就不敢担保鳗鱼 是否会伤害你了
I doubt you'll get such an offer from the eels.
这次她没被鳗鱼吃掉
She doesn't get eaten by the eels at this time.
什么？
What?
鳗鱼不会伤到她的
The eel doesn't get her.
因为你看起来 有点紧张我正要对你解释
I'm explaining to you because you look nervous.
我没有紧张
I wasn't nervous.
或许我只是有点关心…
Maybe I was a little bit concerned...
但那不是一码事
but that's not the same thing.
如果你想的话 我们可以在此停止
Because we can stop now if you want.
不.如果你愿意的话 还可以再读一点
No. You could read a little bit more, if you want.
“你知道那是什么 声音吗，殿下？”
''Do you know what that sound is, Highness?
“那是鳗鱼的尖叫声”
''Those are the shrieking eels.''
爷爷，这里你已经读过了
Pass that, Grandpa. You read it already.
天啊，是的
My goodness, I did.
不好意思
I'm sorry. Beg your pardon.
好的，好的.我看看
All right, all right. Let's see.
她在水中 鳗鱼跟着她…
She was in the water, the eel was coming after her...
她很害怕…
she was frightened...
鳗鱼开始要攻击她了 然后…
the eel started to charge her, and then...
把她放下.放下她！
Put her down. Just put her down!
我想他更靠近我们了
I think he's getting closer.
他和我们并没关系
He's no concern of ours.
继续航行！
Sail on!
我想你认为 自己很勇敢，对吧？
I suppose you think you're brave, don't you?
只是相对一些人是
Only compared to some.
看！他就要赶上我们了！
Look! He's right on top of us!
我在想他用的风力 是否和我们一样
I wonder if he's using the same wind we are using.
无论他是谁 都太迟了.看到了吧？
Whoever he is, he's too late. See?
疯狂之巅！
The Cliffs of Insanity!
快点！
Hurry up!
动一下这家伙！
Move the thing!
还有那个
And that other thing!
快点
Move it!
我们安全了
We're safe.
只有菲兹克 才有这个能力
Only Fezzik is strong enough to go up our way.
他能找到停泊点 也要花好几个小时
He'll have to sail for hours till he finds a harbor.
他也在爬绳 他紧跟着我们
He's climbing the rope, and he's gaining on us!
不可想像！
Inconceivable!
快点！
Faster!
我想我已经很快了
I thought I was going faster.
巨人就像你这样啊…
You were supposed to be this colossus...
你本应是 最有力量的东西…
you were this great legendary thing...
而他就要追上我们了！
and yet he gains!
我带上了三个人 而他只是一个人在爬
I'm carrying three people, and he got only himself.
我不接受解释. 我得找一个新的巨人
I do not accept excuses. I have to find a new giant.
别这么说，维兹尼，求你了
Don't say that, Vizzini, please.
我是否说得够清楚了 你的工作不保了？
Did I make it clear that your job is at stake?
他的臂力很强
He's got very good arms.
他没掉下去？
He didn't fall?
不可想像！
Inconceivable!
你总是在用这个词
You keep using that word.
我认为那并不意味着 如你所想的意思
I do not think it means what you think it means.
我的天啊，他还在爬
My God, he's climbing.
无论他是谁，他明显也是 冲着我们的公主来的…
Whoever he is, he's obviously seen us with the princess...
因此必须得死
and must therefore die.
你带着她
You carry her.
我们要往基尔德边疆进发
We'll head straight for the Guilder frontier.
他死后再赶上
Catch up when he's dead.
如果他掉了下去，那很好. 如果不是，就用剑
If he falls, fine. If not, the sword.
我来摆平他，左手
I'm going to duel him left-handed.
你也知道我们的时间很紧
You know what a hurry we're in.
这是我唯一满意的方式
It's the only way I can be satisfied.
如果我用右手的话 唉！那太快了
If I use my right, tsk! Over too quickly.
用你自己的方式！
Have it your way!
你小心点
You be careful.
戴着面具的人不可信
People in masks cannot be trusted.
我在等！
I'm waiting!
嗨！
Hello there!
爬得很慢咧？
Slow going?
我不想粗鲁 但这不像看起来那么容易
I don't mean to be rude, but this is not as easy as it looks.
如果你不转移我的注意力 我就感激不尽了
I'd appreciate it if you wouldn't distract me.
-不好意思 -谢谢
- Sorry. - Thank you.
我想你是不可能提速的吧？
I do not suppose you could speed things up?
如果你想快点的话…
If you're in such a hurry...
你可以掉一根绳子 或一根树枝…
you could lower a rope or a tree branch...
或寻找什么有用的方式
or find something useful to do.
我可以.我这儿就有绳…
I could do that. I got some rope up here...
但我想你不会接受 我的帮助的…
but I do not think you would accept my help...
因为我就在 这儿等着要杀你
since I am only waiting around to kill you.
那不会给我们的关系 蒙上阴影
That does put a damper on our relationship.
但我可以保证 等到你爬上来才杀你
But I promise I won't kill you until you reach the top.
那挺好的，但我恐怕 你得等上一阵子了
That's very comforting, but I'm afraid you'll just have to wait.
我讨厌等待
I hate waiting.
我以一个西班牙人 来向你担保
I could give you my word as a Spaniard.
不好
No good.
我认识太多西班牙人了
I've known too many Spaniards.
有什么方式 才能让你信任我？
Any way you'll trust me?
想不出来
Nothing comes to mind.
我对我父亲 多明戈.蒙托亚的灵魂发誓
I swear on the soul of my father, Domingo Montoya...
你会安全抵达顶部
you will reach the top alive.
把绳子抛给我
Throw me the rope.
谢谢
Thank you.
等等.等你准备好了
Wait. We'll wait until you're ready.
谢谢你
Again, thank you.
我不是想探查什么 你的右手是否…
I do not mean to pry, but you don't by any chance...
碰巧有六根手指？
happen to have six fingers on your right hand?
你总是这样开始话题的吗？
Do you always begin conversations this way?
我的父亲是被一个 有六根手指的人杀害的
My father was slaughtered by a six-fingered man.
他是一位出色的铸剑商
He was a great swordmaker, my father.
当一个有六根 手指的人出现…
When the six-fingered man appeared...
并要求打造一把 特别的剑时…
and request a special sword...
我的父亲接受了这份工作
my father took the job.
他花了一年的 心血才打造好
He slaved a year before he was done.
我还从未见过赶上它的
I've never seen its equal.
那六根手指的人 回来并要拿剑…
The six-fingered man returned and demanded it...
但只付他所 承诺过的1/10的价钱
but at 1/10 his promised price.
我父亲拒绝了
My father refused.
拿不到剑…
Without a word...
那六根手指的人就向 我父亲的心脏戳去
the six-fingered man slashed him through the heart.
我爱我的父亲
I loved my father.
所以很自然 我就向那凶手挑战
So naturally, I challenged his murderer to a duel.
我失败了
I failed.
那六根手指的人 留了我这个生口
The six-fingered man leave me alive...
但他留下了这个给我
but he gave me this.
你当时多大？
How old were you?
11岁
I was eleven years old.
当我足够强壮时…
When I was strong enough...
我耗尽我的生命去学剑术
I dedicated my life to the study of fencing.
那么下一次我们会面时 我就不会输了
So the next time we meet, I will not fail.
我会走向那六根手指的人 并对他说…
I will go up to the six-fingered man and say...
“你好”
''Hello.
“我叫埃尼戈.蒙托亚”
''My name is Inigo Montoya.
“你杀了我的父亲”
''You killed my father.
“准备等死吧”
''Prepare to die.''
你什么也不干 就是在学剑术啊？
You've done nothing but study swordplay?
最近更多的是追捕
More pursuit than study lately.
你也看见，我没发现他
You see, I cannot find him.
已经有20年了. 我有点失去信心了
It's been twenty years now. I'm starting to lose confidence.
我只是给 维兹尼效力来还债
I just work for Vizzini to pay the bills.
这对报仇来说并不是大钱
There's not a lot of money in revenge.
我希望某一天你能找到他
I certainly hope you find him someday.
You're ready, then?
准备好了吗 你已足够公平了
Whether I am or not, you've been more than fair.
你看来是很正派的. 我讨厌要杀你
You seem a decent fellow. I hate to kill you.
你似乎也很正派的. 我讨厌死亡
You seem a decent fellow. I hate to die.
开始
Begin.
你是用波尼狄的防卫术 来防御我的？
You are using Bonetti's defense against me?
我想由于这是多岩石地势 这挺适合的
I thought it fitting considering the rocky terrain.
自然，你就肯定想 我用卡波菲洛式来进攻你了
Naturally. You must expect me to attack with Capo Ferro.
自然，我想费鲍尔特式 能抵偿卡波菲洛式
Naturally, but I find that Thibault cancels out Capo Ferro.
是吗？
Don't you?
除非敌方 研究过阿格里帕式
Unless the enemy has studied Agrippa.
这个我有
Which I have.
你真是太出色了！
You are wonderful!
谢谢.我花了很多功夫 才练就成这样的
Thank you. I've worked hard to become so.
我得承认，你比我要棒
I admit it. You are better than I am.
那你为什么还要笑？
Then why are you smiling?
因为我知道一些 你不知道的东西
Because I know something you don't know.
什么？
What is that?
我不是用左手的
I am not left-handed.
你让人惊讶
You're amazing.
我应该是，特别是20年后
I ought to be, after twenty years.
有些事情我也该告诉你的
There's something I ought to tell you.
那就说吧
Tell me.
我也不是左撇子
I'm not left-handed, either.
你是谁？
Who are you?
没人需要推断
No one of consequence.
我得知道
I must know.
那就习惯失望吧
Get used to disappointment.
快点杀我吧
Kill me quickly.
作为一个像你一样的艺术家…
I would sooner destroy a stained-glass window...
我就快毁了一块彩色油画玻璃窗
as an artist like yourself.
然而，我也是不能让你追赶我的
However, since I can't have you following me, either.
请理解，这是最尊重你的做法了
Please understand, I hold you in the highest respect.
不可想像！
Inconceivable!
把她给我！尽快跟上我们！
Give her to me! Catch up with us quickly!
那我该干什么？
What do I do?
了结他，你的方式！
Finish him, finish him... your way!
好的，我的方式. 谢谢，维兹尼
Good, my way. Thank you, Vizzini.
哪种方式是我的方式？
Which way's my way?
捡起一块这些岩石 躲在大石头后
Pick up one of those rocks, get behind the boulder.
等一下…
In a few minutes...
黑衣人就会上来
the man in black will come running around the bend.
你一看见他的头 就用这岩石砸他就是了
The minute his head is in view, hit it with the rock!
我的方式似乎 没什么体育精神
My way is not very sportsmanlike.
我是有意的
I did that on purpose.
我本不会失手
I didn't have to miss.
我相信你
I believe you.
那现在怎样？
So what happens now?
我们在上帝的谕旨下碰面
We face each other as God intended.
要有体育精神点
Sportsmanlike.
不耍花招，不用武器. 技术对技术
No tricks, no weapons. Skill against skill alone.
你会扔掉你的岩石 而我放下我的剑…
You'll put down your rock, and I'll put down my sword...
然后我们就要像文明人 一样杀死对方？
and we'll try and kill each other like civilized people?
我现在可以杀你了
I could kill you now.
坦白说，徒手搏斗的话…
Frankly, I think the odds...
机率有点偏向于你这一方
are slightly in your favor at hand-fighting.
长得大和强壮不是我的错
It's not my fault being the biggest and the strongest.
我还没练习过呢
I don't even exercise.
你就想这样和我浪费时间 还是怎么着？
Are you just fiddling around with me, or what?
我想让你觉得你干得不赖
I want you to feel you are doing well.
我不想让人们 在羞辱中死去
I hate for people to die embarrassed.
你动作很快！
You're quick!
好的
Good thing, too!
你为什么要戴面具？
Why are you wearing a mask?
是不是给硫酸伤过 还是怎样的？
Were you burned with acid or something like that?
不.只是这样很舒服
No. It's just they're terribly comfortable.
我想将来所有人 都会戴这个
I think everyone will be wearing them in the future.
我只是在想你怎么给 我找这么多r烦
I just figured why you give me so much trouble.
为什么这样，你想过吗？
Why is that, do you think?
我还没和一个人 打过这么久的
I haven't fought just one person for so long.
我专攻一群人
I've been specializing in groups.
当地慈善团体的格斗帮…
Battling gangs for local charities...
诸如此类的东西
that kind of thing.
这力量这么会不一样？
Why should that make such a... Oof! Difference?
噢，你明白了吧…
Well, you see...
当你和矮你 一截的人打斗时…
you use different moves...
和当你和一个人打斗时…
when you're fighting half a dozen people...
你得用…
than when you only...
不同的移动步法
have to be worried about one.
当你醒的时候，我不会 妒忌你的头痛的
I do not envy you the headache you will have when you awake.
但与此同时，好好地休息 去梦见你的大块头女人吧
But in the meantime, rest well and dream of large women.
这是…
There was...
一场伟大的决斗
a mighty duel.
到处都有痕迹
It ranged all over.
他们都是大师
They were both masters.
谁赢了？结果是怎样？
Who won? How did it end?
败方自己走了…
The loser ran off alone...
而赢家就跟着这些 朝着基尔德的脚印进发了
while the winner... followed those footprints toward Guilder.
我们两个都跟踪吗？
Shall we track them both?
败方没什么大不了
The loser is nothing.
只是要公主的下落
Only the princess matters.
很显然 这都是基尔德战士的计划
Clearly, this was all planned by warriors of Guilder.
我们要对前面的 任何情况做好准备
We must all be ready for whatever lies ahead.
这会不会是一个陷阱？
Could this be a trap?
我一直都认为所有 一切都可能是一个陷阱
I always think everything could be a trap.
这就是我为什么 还活着的原因
That is why I'm still alive.
终于我们会面了
So, it is down to you, and it is down to me.
如果你想要她的人头…
If you wish her dead...
你就继续向前走
by all means, keep moving forward.
我来解释一下
Let me explain.
没什么好解释的
There's nothing to explain.
你想绑架我正当 偷回来的东西啊
You're trying to kidnap what I've rightfully stolen.
或许一个协议可以达成
Perhaps... an arrangement can be reached.
没什么协议，你想杀她啊
There will be no arrangement, and you're killing her.
如果没协议的话 那么我们就处于僵局了
If there can be no arrangement, then we are at an impasse.
我恐怕是
I'm afraid so.
我不能和你相比 体格上的…
I can't compete with you physically...
而你的脑子就比不上我
and you're no match for my brains.
你这么聪明啊？
You're that smart?
这样吧…
Let me put it this way...
你有没听说过柏拉图 亚里斯多德，苏格拉底？
have you ever heard of Plato, Aristotle, Socrates?
-有 -都是蠢蛋
- Yes. - Morons.
是吗？
Really?
这样的话，我就得以 一场智慧的斗争来挑战你了
In that case, I challenge you to a battle of wits.
为了公主？
For the princess?
为了死亡？
To the death?
我接受
I accept.
好的，倒酒
Good, then pour the wine.
闻一下，别碰
Inhale this, but do not touch.
我闻不到什么
I smell nothing.
你闻不出来的是一种叫艾厄藤粉的毒物
What you do not smell is called iocane powder.
它无色无味 在液体中能讯速溶解…
It is odorless, tasteless, dissolves instantly in liquid...
是已知最毒毒药中的一种
and is among the more deadly poisons known to man.
好的.有毒的是哪杯？
All right. Where is the poison?
智慧之战开始了
The battle of wits has begun.
由你来决定 然后我们都喝…
It ends when you decide, and we both drink...
接着就可以 发现谁是正确…
and find out who is right...
而谁要死
and who is dead.
那还不简单
But it's so simple.
我要做根据我所认识的 你来进行猜测…
All I have to do is divine from what I know of you...
猜一下你是哪种人…
are you the sort of man...
是会把毒药放进自己的 杯里还是敌人的杯里？
who would put the poison into his own goblet or his enemy's?
一个聪明的人会把毒药…
A clever man would put the poison...
放进他自己的杯了…
into his own goblet...
因为他知道 只有绝顶蠢蛋…
because he would know that only a great fool...
才会接受别人给的东西
would reach for what he was given.
我不是绝顶蠢蛋…
I am not a great fool...
所以我就很明显 不会选择你面前的酒
so I can clearly not choose the wine in front of you.
但你也肯定知道 我不是一个绝顶蠢蛋
But you must have known I was not a great fool.
你可能指望过…
You would have counted on it...
那么我也很明显 不会现在我面前的酒
so I can clearly not choose the wine in front of me.
你作出决定了？
You've made your decision, then?
还没有…
Not remotely...
因为这种毒药来这澳大利亚 这是众所周知的了…
because iocane comes from Australia, as everyone knows...
而澳大利亚都是些罪犯…
and Australia is entirely peopled with criminals...
罪犯习惯于让 人们不相信他们…
and criminals are used to having people not trust them...
正如我不相信你…
as you are not trusted by me...
那么我就很明显 不去选择你面前的酒
so I can clearly not choose the wine in front of you.
真的 你有令人混乱的智慧
Truly, you have a dizzying intellect.
等我做选择吧！
Wait till I get going!
-我在哪儿？ -澳大利亚
- Where was I? - Australia.
对，澳大利亚. 你肯定会怀疑…
Yes, Australia. You must have suspected...
我就会知道 这些毒药的来源…
I would have known the powder's origin...
所以我就很明显不去 选择我面前的酒
so I can clearly not choose the wine in front of me.
你现在在拖延时间
You're just stalling now.
你想这样想是吧？
You'd like to think that, wouldn't you?
你打赢了我的巨人…
You've beaten my giant...
这就意味着你很强壮…
which means you're exceptionally strong...
那么你就会把毒药 放进你的杯子…
so you could have put the poison in your own goblet...
相信你的力量 能解救你…
trusting on your strength to save you...
那么我就不会 选择你面前的酒
so I can clearly not choose the wine in front of you.
但你又比我的 西班牙人要好…
But you've also bested my Spaniard...
这就意味着 你肯定研究过…
which means you must have studied...
你肯定研究过人的精神…
and in studying, you must have learned that man is mortal...
所以你会把毒药…
so you would have put the poison...
置于远离你自己的地方…
as far from yourself as possible...
所以我就很明显不会 去选择我面前的酒
so I can clearly not choose the wine in front of me.
你想耍我，提供一些暗示
You're trying to trick me into giving away something.
没用的
It won't work.
有用.你已经给出了
It has worked. You've given everything away.
-我知道毒药放在哪杯了 -那么做决定吧
- I know where the poison is. - Then make your choice.
我会的，而我选择… 那泥土上的是什么东西？
I will, and I choose... What in the world can that be?
什么？哪里？
What? Where?
我没看见什么
I don't see anything.
有什么我会用剑杀了它的
I could have sworn I saw something. No matter.
有什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
待会我告诉你
I'll tell you in a minute.
首先，我们喝吧…
First, let's drink...
我喝我的，你喝你的
me from my glass and you from yours.
你猜错了
You guessed wrong.
你只是想我猜错了. 那真是好笑！
You only think I guessed wrong. That's what's so funny!
你转过身时，我调了杯子
I switched glasses when your back was turned!
你这个蠢蛋！
You fool!
你成了经典大错中的 一个受害者
You fell victim to one of the classic blunders.
最著名的 “别陷入亚洲地区的战役”
The most famous is ''Never get involved in a land war in Asia.''
但有点比不上…
But only slightly less well known is this...
“死神来临时 别于西西里岛人对抗”
''Never go in against a Sicilian when death is on the line! ''
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是不能被嘲弄的人
I am no one to be trifled with.
那就是你所需要知道的
That is all you ever need know.
我风才一直在想…
And to think, all that time...
你在哪个杯子放了毒药
it was your cup that was poisoned.
两只都放了
They were both poisoned.
我花了好几年时间…
I spent the last few years...
来形此对艾厄藤的免疫
building up an immunity to iocane powder.
有人打晕了巨人
Someone has beaten the giant.
如果她死的话 基尔德就要受灾害
There will be great suffering in Guilder if she dies.
透一下气吧
Catch your breath.
如果你放了我…
If you'll release me...
无论你要求什么作为赎金 你都会得到的.我答应你
whatever you ask for ransom, you'll get it. I promise you.
一个女人的承诺 有什么价值？
And what is that worth... the promise of a woman?
你真的很搞笑，殿下
You're very funny, Highness.
我给你一次机会
I was giving you a chance.
无论你把我带到哪儿…
It does not matter where you take me...
没有比胡姆普丁克王子 更棒的猎人了
there is no greater hunter than Prince Humperdinck.
他能在乌云密布中 找到猎鹰
He can track a falcon on a cloudy day.
他会找到你的
He can find you.
你认为你的 至爱会救你吗？
You think your dearest love will save you?
我从来就没说过 他是我的至爱
I never said he was my dearest love.
但，是的，他会来救我. 这是我知道的
And, yes, he will save me. That I know.
你就向我承认 你不爱你的未婚夫了
You admit to me you do not love your fiancé.
他知道我并不爱他
He knows I do not love him.
你的意思是不值得去爱了
Are not capable of love is what you mean.
我曾经深深的爱过…
I have loved more deeply...
这不是像你 这样的凶手能想像的
than a killer like yourself could ever dream.
这只是一个警告，殿下
That was a warning, Highness.
下次，我的手就会挥下去了
The next time, my hand flies on its own.
我出生的地方 如果女人说谎是会受到惩罚的
Where I come from, there are penalties when a woman lies.
艾厄藤，我敢断定…
Iocane. I'd bet my life on it...
这些是公主的脚印
and there are the princess' footprints.
她还活着 或者说一个小时前是
She is alive, or was an hour ago.
当我找到她 她不是还活着时
If she is otherwise when I find her...
我会非常愤怒
I shall be very put out.
-休息吧，殿下 -我知道你是谁
- Rest, Highness. - I know who you are.
你的残酷说明了一切
Your cruelty reveals everything.
你就是可怕的 罗伯茨海盗.承认吧
You're the Dread Pirate Roberts. Admit it.
很荣幸. 有什么需要为你效劳的？
With pride. What can I do for you?
你会慢慢的死去 被碎尸万段
You can die slowly, cut into a thousand pieces.
严厉的恭维啊，殿下
Hardly complimentary, Your Highness.
你为什么要 这么恶毒的诅咒我？
Why loose your venom on me?
你杀了我的爱人
You killed my love.
有可能
It's possible.
我杀了很多人
I kill a lot of people.
谁是你的爱人？
Who was this love of yours?
另一个像这样的王子… 丑陋，富有还有口吃？
Another prince like this one... ugly, rich, and scabby?
一个农场小伙，穷困
A farm boy, poor.
穷困但眼睛很美 就像暴风雨后的大海
Poor and perfect with eyes like the sea after a storm.
就在那大海 你的船进行了袭击
On the high seas, your ship attacked.
而可怕的海盗罗伯茨 是从来不留俘虏的
And the Dread Pirate Roberts never takes prisoners.
我不能担保会有例外
I can't afford to make exceptions.
一旦有话透露出 海盗会很温柔…
Once word leaks out that a pirate has gone soft...
人们就会违抗你…
people begin to disobey you...
那么除了劳动就没别的了
and then it's nothing but work, work, work all the time.
你刺痛了我的伤口
You mock my pain.
生命就是痛苦，殿下
Life is pain, Highness.
如果有人说得不同 就是在显示其它别的
Anyone who says differently is selling something.
我想我还记得 你的那位农场小伙
I remember this farm boy of yours, I think.
那该是五年前的事了吧？
This would be, what, five years ago?
你听着会难受吗？
Does it bother you to hear?
你说的任何东西 都不会让我难过
Nothing you can say will upset me.
他死得很安祥
He died well.
这该会让你高兴吧
That should please you.
没什么要求，或又哭又闹
No bribe attempts or blubbering.
他只是简单的说，“拜托…”
He simply said, ''Please...
“拜托，我要活着”
''please, I need to live.''
就是这个拜托勾起了 我的记忆
It was the please that caught my memory.
我问他有什么这么重要
I asked him what was so important.
“真爱”，他回答说
''True love,'' he replied.
接着他就提起了一位女孩…
Then he spoke of a girl...
她不但漂亮而且忠诚
of surpassing beauty and faithfulness.
我可以猜想他是指你
I can only assume he meant you.
你该祝福我在他发现你
You should bless me for destroying him...
本来面目时杀了他
before he found out what you really are.
我是谁？
And what am I?
他所说起的忠诚
Faithfulness he talked of, madam...
你忠贞不渝的忠诚
your enduring faithfulness.
老实对我说 当你知道他死了…
Tell me truly. When you found out he was gone...
你是立即就和王子订婚…
did you get engaged to your prince that same hour...
还是为了表示对 他的哀悼而等了一个星期？
or did you wait a whole week out of respect for the dead?
你又一次伤害了我. 别这样做了！
You mocked me once. Never do it again!
那天我也死了！
I died that day!
你也可去死了， 我只关心这个
You can die, too, for all I care!
遵你所愿！
As... you... wish!
我亲爱的维斯特雷
My sweet Westley.
我究竟干了什么？
What have I done?
他们消失了
They've disappeared.
他肯定是看到 我们逼近了…
He must've seen us closing in...
这就会使得 他惊惶失措而导致错误
which might account for his panicking into error.
除非我是错的 我没错过…
Unless I'm wrong, and I am never wrong...
他们是朝火沼泽走去了
they are headed dead into the Fire Swamp.
你还能动吗？
Can you move at all?
动？你还活着
Move? You're alive.
如果你愿意，我可以飞
If you want, I can fly.
我告诉过你 我会出现在身边的
I told you I would always come for you.
你为什么不等我？
Why didn't you wait for me?
噢…
Well...
你死了
you were dead.
死亡不能阻止真爱
Death cannot stop true love.
死亡能做的 只是耽搁一会儿
All it can do is delay it for a while.
我再也不会再怀疑了
I will never doubt again.
永远也没有这个需要了
There will never be a need.
噢，不.拜托
Oh, no. No, please.
怎么了？有问题吗？
What is it? What's the matter?
他们又接吻了
They're kissing again.
我们一定要 听那些接吻的部分吗？
Do we have to hear the kissing part?
某天你或许就不能太介意了
Someday you may not mind so much.
跳读到火沼泽那一部分. 那似乎挺吸引的
Skip on to the Fire Swamp. That sounded good.
你生病.我就随你的意愿吧
You're sick. I'll humor you.
噢，我们选择在哪儿？
So now, where were we here?
维斯特雷和布特卡普 就在峡谷里跑
Westley and Buttercup raced along the ravine floor.
你的蠢蛋未婚夫太慢了
Your pig fiancé is too late.
再走一下 我们就会安全到达火沼泽了
A few more steps, and we'll be safe in the Fire Swamp.
我们会活不了命的
We'll never survive.
胡说！你这样说只是 因为没人试过
Nonsense! You only say that because no one ever has.
没那么糟糕
It's not that bad.
我不是说我想在那儿 搭建一间避暑房子
I'm not saying I'd like to build a summer home here...
但这些树的确很可爱
but the trees are actually quite lovely.
噢，现在，那是个奇遇
Well, now, that was an adventure.
烧焦了一点，是吧？
Singed a bit, were you?
你呢？
You?
我得说一句…
One thing I will say...
火沼让你得在意你的脚趾
the fire swamp certainly does keep you on your toes.
但这就很快变成 一个快乐的回忆…
This will all soon be but a happy memory...
因为罗伯茨的船在 很远的地方抛锚…
because Roberts' ship Revenge is anchored at the far end...
而正如你所知的我 就是罗伯茨
and I, as you know, am Roberts.
这怎么可能…
How is that possible...
由于他已经抢劫了20年…
since he's been marauding twenty years...
而你只是在五年前 离开我的啊
and you only left me five years ago?
我自己也经常惊讶于 生命中的一些急转弯
I myself am often surprised at life's little quirks.
而我之前和你说的 关于“拜托”是真的
What I told you before about saying please was true.
那激起了罗伯茨的兴趣…
It intrigued Roberts...
特别是当我向 他描述你的美丽时
as did my description of your beauty.
最后 罗伯茨决定了一些事情
Finally, Roberts decided something.
他说，“好的，维斯特雷 我从未有男仆”
He said, ''All right, Westley, I've never had a valet.
“你今晚就可以试试”
''You can try it for tonight.
“我到早上会把你杀了”
''I'll most likely kill you in the morning.''
他说了三年这个
Three years he said that.
“晚安，维斯特雷 干得好.睡个好觉吧”
''Good night, Westley, good work. Sleep well.
“我到早上会把你杀了”
''I'll most likely kill you in the morning.''
对我来说，是一个愉快的时间
It was a fine time for me.
我学会了剑术，搏斗 任何人教给我的任何东西
I was learning to fence, fight, anything anyone would teach me.
罗伯茨和我最后变成了朋友…
And Roberts and I eventually became friends...
那么就可能发生了
and then it happened.
什么？继续说
What? Go on.
罗伯茨很富有了 他要引退…
Roberts had grown so rich, he wanted to retire...
所以他就把我带到他的小屋 告诉我他的秘密
so he took me to his cabin and told me his secret.
“我不是那可怕的 罗伯茨海盗”，他说
''I am not the Dread Pirate Roberts,'' he said.
“我叫赖安”
''My name is Ryan.
“我是从前度罗伯茨 继承了这艘船的”
''I inherited the ship from the previous Roberts...
“就好像你会从我这儿 继承这艘船一样”
''just as you will inherit it from me.
“而那个让我继承的人 也不是真正的罗伯茨”
''The man I inherited it from wasn't the real Roberts, either.
“他叫坎波布德”
''His name was Cumberbund.
“真正的罗伯茨 已经引退15年了”
''The real Roberts has been retired fifteen years...
“就好像一位皇帝 一样生活着.”谢谢
''and living like a king.'' Thank you.
接着他解释名字是 一件很重要的事情…
Then he explained the name was the important thing...
因为这可以激发 必要的威严
for inspiring the necessary fear.
否则没人会臣服于 可怕的海盗维斯特雷
You see, no one would surrender to the Dread Pirate Westley.
所以我们向岸边航行 招了一批新的海员
So we sailed ashore, took on an entirely new crew.
而他在船上逗留了 一会儿辅助我…
And he stayed aboard for a while as first mate...
总是把我称呼为罗伯茨
all the time calling me Roberts.
直到成员们都信服了 他就离开了船…
Once the crew believed, he left the ship...
自那以后我 就一直是罗伯茨
and I have been Roberts ever since.
直到现在我们重逢了…
Except, now that we're together...
我可以引退并把 这个名字传给别人
I shall retire and hand the name over to someone else.
还有什么不明白的吗？
Is everything clear to you?
我们不会成功的
We'll never succeed.
我们会死在这儿的
We may as well die here.
不，我们已经成功了
No, we have already succeeded.
我是说，火沼泽里的 三个的恐怖是什么？
I mean, what are the three terrors of the Fire Swamp?
一个是火焰喷射.这没问题
One, the flame spurt. No problem.
前面有一些可怕的声音
There's a popping sound preceding each.
我们可以避开
We can avoid that.
第二是闪电沙
Two, the lightning sand.
但你这么聪明可能会 发现那是什么样子的
But you were clever enough to discover what that looks like...
这样的话，我们也可以避免
so in the future, we can avoid that, too.
维斯特雷 那么异常的肉食动物呢？
Westley, what about the R.O.U.S. S?
就是块头异常大的 肉食动物啊？
Rodents of Unusual Size?
我想他们并不存在
I don't think they exist.
我们成功了
We did it.
现在，还觉得这么可怕吗？
Now, was that so terrible?
投降！
Surrender!
你是指你想向我投降啊？
You mean you wish to surrender to me?
那好啊，我接受
Very well. I accept.
你的勇敢我给你满分
I give you full marks for bravery.
别把自己当傻子
Don't make yourself a fool.
你是怎样捉到我们的？
But how will you capture us?
我们知道火沼泽的秘密
We know the secrets of the Fire Swamp.
我们可以在那儿快活 地住上一阵子…
We can live there quite happily for some time...
那如果你想要死的话 就随便去参观一下
so whenever you feel like dying, feel free to visit.
我再说一遍，投降！
I tell you once again, surrender!
不可能
It will not happen.
最后一次，投降！
For the last time, surrender!
先死吧
Death first!
你能答应不去伤害他吗？
Will you promise not to hurt him?!
-什么？ -什么？
- What was that? - What was that?
如果我们投降 而且我跟你回去…
If we surrender and I return with you...
你能答应不去 伤害这个人吗？
will you promise not to hurt this man?
我可以活上千年并不再打猎吗？
May I live a thousand years and never hunt again.
他是海盗船上的一位海员
He is a sailor on the pirate ship Revenge.
答应把他送回他的船上
Promise to return him to his ship.
我答应可以
I swear it will be done.
一旦看不见我们后 就把他带回弗罗林…
Once we're out of sight, take him back to Florin...
把他扔进绝望渊里
and throw him in the Pit of Despair.
我答应可以
I swear it will be done.
我想你已经死了一次 这已经让我受不了了
I thought you were dead once, and it almost destroyed me.
我不能忍受你又死一次…
I could not bear it if you died again...
特别是我能救你时
not when I could save you.
来吧，先生
Come, sir.
我们得把你带回到你的船上
We must get you to your ship.
我们是大男人
We are men of action.
说谎不是我们的作风
Lies do not become us.
说的好，先生
Well spoken, sir.
那是什么？
What is it?
你的右手有六根手指
You have six fingers on your right hand.
有人会来找你的
Someone was looking for you.
我在哪儿？
Where am I?
绝望渊
The Pit of Despair.
可别指望…
Don't even think...
可别指望想逃
Don't even think about trying to escape.
手铐够粗的了
The chains are far too thick.
也别指望被解救
And don't dream of being rescued, either.
进来的方法非常秘密
The only way in is secret.
只有王子，伯爵和我…
Only the prince, the count, and I...
知道如何进出
know how to get in and out.
那么我就得待在 这儿直到我死了？
Then I'm here till I die?
直到他们要杀你
Till they kill you, yeah.
那你为什么 还要给我疗伤？
Then why bother curing me?
王子和伯爵坚持 被抓进来的人在受刑前…
The prince and count insist on everyone being healthy...
必须是安全的
before they're broken.
那就会有一个酷刑咯
So it's to be torture.
我能应付得了酷刑
I can cope with torture.
你不相信我啊？
You don't believe me?
你能在火沼泽里活命
You survived the Fire Swamp.
你肯定是非常勇敢的…
You must be very brave...
但没人能抵挡得了机器
but nobody withstands the Machine.
自从火沼泽出来后 她就一直是这样了
She's been like that ever since the Fire Swamp.
那是我父亲每况 愈下的健康让她难过
It's my father's failing health that's upsetting her.
当然了
Of course.
皇上死的那晚…
The king died that very night...
和第二天的黎明…
and before the following dawn...
布特卡普 和胡姆普丁克结婚
Buttercup and Humperdinck were married.
而中午 她会再会见她的国民…
And at noon, she met her subjects again...
而这次是他们的皇后
this time, as their queen.
我父亲的遗言是…
My father's final words were...
等等，等等！爷爷
Hold it! Hold it, Grandpa.
你读错了
You read that wrong.
她不是和胡姆普丁克结婚 而是和维斯特雷结婚
She doesn't marry Humperdinck. She marries Westley.
我敢肯定这点
I'm just sure of it.
维斯特雷为了她 做了那么多…
After all that Westley did for her...
如果她不嫁给他 那就不公平了
if she didn't marry him, it wouldn't be fair.
谁说生活是公平的？
Who says life is fair?
那想哪儿写过了？
Where is that written?
生活不总是公平的
Life isn't always fair.
我告诉你 你搞混了这个故事！
I'm telling you, you're messing up the story!
噢，理顺它啊！
Now, get it right!
你要我继续这个吗？
Do you want me to go on with this?
好的，那么就别打岔了
All right, then, no more interruptions.
“中午 她会见了她的国民..”
''At noon, she met her subjects again...
“这次是他们的皇后了”
this time, as their queen.''
我父亲的遗言是…
My father's final words were...
“像我一样爱她 那就会是快乐”
''Love her as I loved her, and there will be joy.''
我向你们介绍你们的皇后！
I present to you your queen!
布特卡普皇后！
Queen Buttercup!
你为什么要这样做？
Why do you do this?
你的手中有爱，而你放弃了！
You had love in your hands, and you gave it up!
如果我不这样做了 他们会把维斯特雷杀了
They would have killed Westley if I hadn't done it.
你的真爱还活着 而你要嫁给另外一个人！
Your true love lives, and you marry another!
真爱让 你在火沼泽里活命…
True love saved her in the Fire Swamp...
而她就把真爱 像垃圾一样对待！
and she treated it like garbage!
那就是她，垃圾皇后！
And that's what she is... the Queen of Refuse!
如果你们愿意的话 向她鞠躬吧！
So bow down to her if you want! Bow to her!
向污泥皇后鞠躬吧！
Bow to the Queen of Slime!
亵渎的皇后！
The Queen of Filth!
腐烂的皇后
The Queen of Putrescence!
垃圾！亵渎！腐烂！粪便！
Rubbish! Filth! Slime! Muck!
离结婚还有10天时间
It was ten days till the wedding.
皇上还活着
The king still lived.
但布特卡普的恶梦 紧紧地缠绕着她
But Buttercup's nightmares were growing steadily worse.
是吧？我不是说她不会和那讨厌 胡姆普丁克结婚的吧？
See? Didn't I say she'd never marry that rotten Humperdinck?
对，你非常聪明.闭嘴
Yes, you're very smart. Shut up.
是这样的
It comes to this.
我爱维斯特雷. 我一直都爱着他
I love Westley. I always have.
我也知道他也 一直都爱着我
I know now I always will.
如果你告诉我 我必须10天后嫁给你…
If you tell me I must marry you in ten days...
那请相信我 会在早上死去的
please believe I will be dead by morning.
我从来不想让你不高兴
I could never cause you grief.
想想我们的婚礼取消
Consider our wedding off.
你把维斯特雷…
You returned this...
送回到他的船上了吗？
Westley to his ship?
那我们会警告他
Then we will simply alert him.
宝贝，你真的肯定 他还要你吗？
Beloved... are you certain he still wants you?
毕竟是你在火沼泽里 拆散我们的
After all, it was you who did the leaving in the Fire Swamp.
更别提海盗 会不会守诺言了
Not to mention that pirates are not known as men of their words.
我的维斯特雷总是 会出现在我身边的
My Westley will always come for me.
我提议一个交易
I suggest a deal.
你写四封同样的信
You write four copies of a letter.
我会派遣我最快的四艘船 每艘船往一个方向
I'll send my four fastest ships, one in each direction.
可怕的罗伯茨海盗 每年的这个时候.
The Dread Pirate Roberts...
都是很靠近弗罗林的
is always close to Florin this time of year.
我们会用上白旗 并传达你的信息
We'll run up the white flag and deliver your message.
如果维斯特雷要你的话 那就祝福你们
If Westley wants you, bless you both.
如果不是的话…
If not...
就请答应我别自杀
please consider me as an alternative to suicide.
怎么样？
Are we agreed?
你的公主真的是一个 好胜心很强的人
Your princess is really quite a winning creature.
或许只是小事而已 但她的要求似乎不容否认
A trifle simple, perhaps, but her appeal is undeniable.
我知道.人们都很喜欢她
I know. The people are quite taken with her.
那就奇怪，当我雇维兹尼…
It's odd, but when I hired Vizzini...
在我们订婚的当天杀了她…
to have her murdered on our engagement day...
我想那很聪明
I thought that was clever.
但当我在结婚当晚掐死她…
But it's going to be so much more moving...
就会有很多行动
when I strangle her on our wedding night.
一旦基尔德受遣责…
Once Guilder is blamed...
国家的人们 会处于愤怒的情绪中
the nation will be truly outraged.
他们就会要求我们去作战了
They'll demand we go to war.
噢，那机关在哪儿？
Now, where is that secret knot?
找到它可真r烦
It's impossible to find.
你要不要下去？
Are you coming down into the pit?
维斯特雷体力恢复了
Westley's got his strength back.
我今晚要用机器来炮制他
I'm starting him on the Machine tonight.
蒂龙，你知道我是 多么想看看你的杰作…
Tyrone, you know how much I love watching you work...
但我得去计划一下 我们国家的500周年庆典
but I've got my country's 500th anniversary to plan...
还有怎样安排我的婚礼 如何谋杀我的妻子…
my wedding to arrange, my wife to murder...
还要陷害基尔德. 我都焦头烂额了
and Guilder to frame for it. I'm swamped.
休息一下吧
Get some rest.
如果身体不行 你就一无所有了
If you haven't got your health, you haven't got anything.
漂亮吧？
Beautiful, isn't it?
这花了我生命中 一半的时间来发明的
It took me half a lifetime to invent it.
我想你会发现…
I'm sure you've discovered...
我对痛苦的一种 深深的和持久的兴趣
my deep and abiding interest in pain.
现在我在写 这个问题上的…
At present, I'm writing the definitive work...
权威性的作品
on the subject.
所以呢我要你 老老实实告诉我…
So I want you to be totally honest with me...
这机器让你有什么感觉
on how the Machine makes you feel.
这是我们的第一次尝试 我用最低的设置
This being our first try, I'll use the lowest setting.
正如你所知道的 抽水机的概念…
As you know, the concept of the suction pump...
是很古老了
is centuries old.
噢，真的，就是这样
Well, really, that's all this is.
而除了抽水…
Except that, instead of sucking water...
我还吸取生命
I'm sucking life.
我刚才吸取了 你生命中的一年
I've just sucked one year of your life away.
我会每天 增进一级直到五级…
I might one day go as high as five...
但我真的不知道 那会对你有什么影响…
but I really don't know what that would do to you...
所以就由我们 所掌握的开始吧
so let's just start with what we have.
这对你产生什么影响？ 告诉我
What did this do to you? Tell me.
记住，这是给 子孙后代看的…
And remember, this is for posterity...
所以老实点
so be honest.
你觉得怎样？
How do you feel?
有趣
Interesting.
耶林
Yellin.
阁下
Sire.
作为弗罗林的执行总监 我相信你会保守这个秘密
As chief enforcer of all Florin, I trust you with this secret.
从基尔德来的杀手…
Killers from Guilder...
渗透到了贼林…
are infiltrating the Thieves' Forest...
并计划在我们结婚的 当天晚上谋杀我的新娘
and plan to murder my bride on our wedding night.
我的侦探网络并没 得到这条消息
My spy network has heard no such news.
有没维斯特雷的消息？
Any word from Westley?
还早着呢，我的宝贝
Too soon, my angel.
耐心点
Patience.
他会出现到我身边的
He will come for me.
当然
Of course.
她不会被杀害的
She will not be murdered.
在结婚当天…
On the day of the wedding...
我要清空贼林…
I want the Thieves' Forest emptied...
逮捕所有那里的居民
and every inhabitant arrested.
很多贼都会抵抗
Many of the thieves will resist.
我的日常执行者可能不足够
My regular enforcers will be inadequate.
那就组织一班强制队
Form a brute squad, then!
在我结婚之前 我要清空贼林
I want the Thieves' Forest emptied before I wed.
那不会容易的，阁下
It won't be easy, sire.
试着支配这个世界吧
Try ruling the world sometime.
结婚的日子到了
The day of the wedding arrived.
强制队充分地…
The brute squad had their hands full...
执行着胡姆普丁克的命令
carrying out Humperdinck's orders.
上！上！上！
Up! Up! Up!
快！
Come on! Come on!
-所有人都出来了吗？ -几乎
- Is everybody out? - Almost.
有一个西班牙人 给我制造了点r烦
There's a Spaniard giving us some trouble.
你就还以颜色
Well, you give him some trouble.
走
Move.
我在等你呢，维兹尼
I am waiting for you, Vizzini.
你说让我回到开始，我有啊
You told me to go back to the beginning, so I have.
这就是我的地方 这就是我住的地方
This is where I am, and this is where I'll stay.
我不会走的
I will not be moved.
噢，那儿！
Ho there!
我不会走的. 滚你的“噢，那儿”吧
I do not budge. Keep your ''ho there.''
王子下达了命令
The prince gave orders.
维兹尼也是
So did Vizzini.
当一份工作搞砸了 你就得回到开始
When a job went wrong, you went back to the beginning.
这就是我们得到工作的地方 所以就是一个开始
This is where we got the job, so it's the beginning.
我一直逗留到 维兹尼来找我为止
And I am staying till Vizzini come.
你这个畜生，来这儿！
You brute, come here!
我在等维兹尼
I am waiting for Vizzini.
你真是个刻薄鬼
You surely are a meanie.
是你啊
It's you.
真的
True.
你脸色不好
You don't look so good.
你的气味也不好闻
You don't smell so good, either.
或许吧
Perhaps not.
我觉得挺好的
I feel fine.
菲兹克和埃尼戈又结合了
Fezzik and Inigo were reunited.
在菲兹克照料他酗酒的朋友 恢复健康的同时…
As Fezzik nursed his inebriated friend back to health...
他告诉了 埃尼戈维兹尼的死…
he told Inigo of Vizzini's death...
还有他的宿敌…
and the existence of Count Rugen...
六根手指人的存在
the six-fingered man.
这可花了埃尼戈不少的 时间去寻找的人
Considering Inigo's lifelong search...
他很好地处理着这些信息
he handled the news surprisingly well.
菲兹克非常细心地 照料着埃尼戈的苏醒
Fezzik took great care in reviving Inigo.
够了
That's enough!
那家伙在哪儿？ 我要去杀了他
Where is this Rugen now so I may kill him?
他和王子在古堡里
He's with the prince in the castle...
但古堡的大门有30人把守
but the castle gate is guarded by thirty men.
你能处理多少人？
How many could you handle?
我想不多于10人
I don't think more than ten.
那就留20人给我了
Leaving twenty for me.
即使是我力拼 我也打不了这么多啊
At my best, I could never defeat that many.
我需要维兹尼给我计划一下. 我在战术方面没天赋
I need Vizzini to plan. I have no gift for strategy.
但维兹尼死了
But Vizzini is dead.
不，不是维兹尼
No. Not Vizzini.
我需要的是黑衣人
I need the man in black.
什么？
What?
他用力量击败你了，大人
He bested you with strength, your greatness.
他用钢铁击败我了
He bested me with steel.
他肯定比维兹尼更有头脑
He must have out-thought Vizzini.
能做到这点的人 能计划我的古堡冲击
A man who can do that can plan my castle onslaught any day.
-走吧 -去哪儿？
- Let's go. - Where?
显然是去找那黑衣人了
Find the man in black, obviously.
但你不知道他在哪儿啊
But you don't know where he is.
别说这个惹恼我
Don't bother me with trifles.
20年后…
After twenty years, at last...
我父亲的灵魂最终得到安息
my father's soul will be at peace.
今晚是血腥的一晚！
There will be blood tonight!
起来报告吧
Rise and report.
贼林清空了
The Thieves' Forest is emptied.
30名守卫把守古堡大门
Thirty men guard the castle gate.
加倍
Double it.
我的公主一定得安全
My princess must be safe.
大门就只有一把钥匙…
The gate has but one key...
我拿着呢
and I carry that.
我的亲爱
My dulcet darling!
今晚，我们就结婚了
Tonight, we marry.
明天早上，你的人民就会护送 我们到弗罗林海峡…
Tomorrow morning, your men will escort us to Florin Channel...
我舰队里的每一艘船…
where every ship in my armada...
等待着护送我们度蜜月
waits to accompany us on our honeymoon.
你是指除了你那 四只快船的每一艘船吧
Every ship but your four fastest, you mean.
除了你派遣的 四只快船的每一艘船
Every ship but the four you sent.
是的，当然
Yes, of course.
自然不是那四只啦
Naturally, not those four.
告退
Your Majesties.
你从来就没派遣过船
You never sent the ships.
别再撒谎了
Don't bother lying.
没关系的
It doesn't matter.
维斯特雷无论如何 都会出现在我身边的
Westley will come for me, anyway:
你真是一个傻姑娘
You're a silly girl.
是的，我是一个傻姑娘…
Yes, I am a silly girl...
而很快我就会看到你除了 是一个懦夫就一无是处
for not having seen sooner that you were nothing but a coward...
内心充满的是恐惧
with a heart full of fear.
如果我是你的话 我就不会说出这些话
I would not say such things if I were you.
为什么不？ 你伤害不了我的
Why not? You can't hurt me.
维斯特雷和我已经 由于爱而紧紧的相连了
Westley and I are joined by the bonds of love...
而你是跟踪不了的…
and you cannot track that...
即使有一千只侦探犬
not with a thousand bloodhounds...
也打断不了…
and you cannot break it...
即使有一千把剑
not with a thousand swords.
而当我说你是一个懦夫时…
And when I say you are a coward...
那是因为你是一个 爬在这一块土地上….
that is only because you are the slimiest weakling...
最懦弱的东西
ever to crawl the earth.
如果我是你的话 我就不会说出这些话！
I would not say such things if I were you!
你是真的爱着对方…
You truly love each other...
那么你会真正的快乐着
and so you might have been truly happy.
无论故事书怎样说.
Not one couple in a century has that chance...
这个世纪里没有 一对夫妇有这样的机会
no matter what the storybooks say.
所以我想这个世纪里 没有一个男人…
So I think no man in a century...
会遭受你一样大的痛苦
will suffer as greatly as you will.
别提到第五级！
Not to fifty!
听.你听见了吗？
Listen. Do you hear?
那是最极端痛苦的叫喊声
That is the sound of ultimate suffering.
当雷根杀我父亲时 我的心就出现了那样的喊声
My heart made that sound when Rugen slaughtered my father.
现在是黑衣的叫声
The man in black makes it now.
黑衣人？
The man in black?
他的爱人今晚要 和另外一个男人结婚
His true love is marrying another tonight.
谁还会有叫出这种 极端痛苦喊声的理由？
Who else has the cause for ultimate suffering?
不好意思.那很重要的
Excuse me. Pardon me, it's important.
菲兹克，请
Fezzik, please.
所有人，走开！
Everybody, move!
谢谢
Thank you.
黑衣人在哪儿？
Where is the man in black?
你从这树林里到那儿的 是吧？
You get there from this grove, yes?
菲兹克 激活一下他的记忆
Fezzik, jog his memory.
不好意思，埃尼戈
I'm sorry, Inigo.
我没想会这么大力的敲他的
I didn't mean to jog him so hard.
父亲，20年来我都没成功过
Father, I have failed you for twenty years.
现在我们的痛苦到尽头了
Now our misery can end.
某个地方…
Somewhere...
附近的某个地方 有一个人能帮助我们
somewhere close by is a man who can help us.
我自己找不到他
I cannot find him alone.
我需要你的帮助
I need you.
我需要你来指示我的剑
I need you to guide my sword.
拜托
Please.
指示我的剑吧
Guide my sword.
他死了
He's dead.
这是不公平的
It just is not fair.
爷爷，等等！
Grandpa, wait!
等等.菲兹克所说的 “他死了”是什么意思？
Wait. What did Fezzik mean, ''He's dead''?
我是说，他不会指死亡吧
I mean, he didn't mean dead.
维斯特雷只是假装…对吧？
Westley's only faking... right?
你要我读还是不要？
You want me to read this or not?
谁去收拾胡姆普丁克？
Who gets Humperdinck?
我不明白
I don't understand.
谁最终杀了胡姆普丁克王子？
Who kills Prince Humperdinck at the end?
有人得这么干
Somebody's got to do it.
是埃尼戈？还是谁？
Is it Inigo? Who?
没人.没人杀他
Nobody. Nobody kills him.
他活下去了
He lives.
你是说他赢了
You mean he wins?
天啊，爷爷，你为什么 要念这个给我听啊？
Jesus, Grandpa, what did you read me this thing for?
你有点虚弱…
You've been very sick...
你对这个故事太较真了
and you're taking this story very seriously.
我想我们现在该停了
I think we ought to stop now.
不.我没事
No. I'm OK.
坐下.我很好
Sit down. I'm all right.
好的，让我看看 我们说到哪儿了？
All right, now, let's see, where were we?
绝望渊
In the Pit of Despair.
我们蒙托亚人 从来不会轻易被打败
We Montoyas have never taken defeat easily.
走吧，菲兹克.把尸体带上
Come along, Fezzik. Bring the body.
这尸体？
The body?
你有钱吗？
Have you any money?
有一点点
I have a little.
我只是希望足够 能买到一个奇迹，就这样
I just hope it's enough to buy a miracle, that's all.
走！
Go away!
什么？
What? What?
你是魔法师马克斯吗…
Are you the Miracle Max...
就是这些年来一直 为皇上效力的那个？
who worked for the king all those years?
皇上的混蛋儿子解雇我了
The king's stinking son fired me.
并感谢你提起了 这么一件让我痛苦的事情
And thank you for bringing up such a painful subject.
如果你是的话 怎么不给我一个漂亮的纸杯…
While you're at it, why don't you give me a nice paper cut...
然后倒点柠檬汁？
and pour lemon juice on it?
我们关门了！
We're closed!
走吧，否则我就得 叫强制队过来了
Beat it, or I'll call the brute squad.
我就是强制队的
I'm on the brute squad.
你就是强制队的
You are the brute squad.
我们需要一个奇迹. 这很重要的
We need a miracle. It's very important.
听着，我退休了. 而且…
Look, I'm retired. And besides...
为什么你们还要找一个被 皇帝混蛋儿子解雇了的人啊？
why would you want someone the king's stinking son fired?
我可能会杀死你让我施法的人
I might kill whoever you wanted me to miracle.
他已经死了
He's already dead.
他是，对吗？
He is, huh?
我来看看.带他进来
I'll take a look. Bring him in.
我看更糟糕点
I've seen worse.
先生？
Sir?
我们很赶时间的
We're in a terrible rush.
别催我，伙计
Don't rush me, sonny.
你催促一个制造奇迹的人 你会得到一个糟糕的奇迹的
You rush a miracle man, you get rotten miracles.
你有钱吗？
You got money?
65元
Sixty-five.
才这么少钱，我是从没干过
I never worked for so little...
除了一次 那是一次非常高尚的缘由
except once, and that was a very noble cause.
这也是非常高尚啊，先生
This is noble, sir.
他的妻子残废了
His wife is crippled.
他的儿子处于饿死的边缘
His children are on the brink of starvation.
你是一个无能的大话精！
Are you a rotten liar!
我需要他来帮助我报父仇
I need him to help avenge my father...
我父亲是20年前被杀的
murdered these twenty years.
你的第一故事好点 风箱在哪儿？
Your first story was better. Where's that bellows?
他或许欠了你的钱 对吧？噢，我来问问他
He probably owes you money, huh? Well, I'll ask him.
他死了.不能说话
He's dead. He can't talk.
谁会知道这么多啊？
Look who knows so much, huh?
正碰巧你的朋友 只是几乎要死了
It just so happens your friend is only mostly dead.
几乎要死和 完完全全死是两马事
There's a big difference between mostly dead and all dead.
张开他的嘴
Please open his mouth.
噢，“几乎要死” 还有点人气
Now, mostly dead is slightly alive.
而完完全全死的话…
Now, all dead... well, with all dead...
通常就只有一件事你能做了
there's usually only one thing that you can do.
什么？
What's that?
搜一下他的衣服看有没钱
Go through his clothes and look for loose change.
喂！
Hello in there!
什么是重要的？
What's so important?
你来这儿觉得什么 值得你活下去？
What you got here that's worth living for?
真爱
Tr-u-u-ue lo-o-o-ove.
真爱.你听见了吗？
True love. You heard him?
你问不出一个 比这个更高尚的理由了吧
You could not ask for a more noble cause than that.
嘿，伙计…
Hey, sonny...
真爱是世界上最伟大的…
true love is the greatest thing in the world...
除了美味的M.L.T….
except for a nice M.L. T...
也就是羊肉 生菜和西红柿三文治…
mutton, lettuce, and tomato sandwich...
特别是新鲜的羊肉 和成熟的西红柿
when the mutton is nice and lean and the tomato is ripe.
太棒了.我喜欢
They're so perky. I love that.
但这可不是他所说的
But that's not what he said.
他显然是要说，“blave”
He distinctly said, ''To bl-a-a-ave.''
我们也知道“blave” 意思是诈骗，对吧？
And as we all know, to blave means to bluff, huh?
所以呢，你或许就在耍花招 而他就在欺骗
So you were probably playing cards, and he cheated...
大话精！
Liar!
回去，巫婆！
Get back, witch!
我不是巫婆！ 我是你的妻子！
I'm not a witch! I'm your wife!
但你那样说之后…
But after what you just said...
我不敢肯定 我是否还要这个名分
I'm not even sure I want to be that anymore!
你从未这么好过
You never had it so good.
他说真爱，马克斯
He said true love, Max.
别说其它话了，瓦莱丽
Don't say another word, Valerie!
他怕了
He's afraid.
自从胡姆普丁克王子 解雇他之后…
Ever since Prince Humperdinck fired him...
他的自信心就摇动了
his confidence is shattered.
你为什么要提起那个名字？
Why'd you say that name?
你向我答应过以后 都不提这个名字的！
You promised me that you would never say that name!
什么？胡姆普丁克！
What? Humperdinck?
我听不见！
I'm not listening!
一条生命就要结束了…
A life expiring...
而你却没勇气说 为什么不帮一帮呢？
and you don't have the decency to say why you won't help!
-没人听见任何东西！ -胡姆普丁克！
- Nobody's hearing nothing! - Humperdinck!
这是布特卡普的真爱
This is Buttercup's true love.
如果你治愈他 他就会阻止胡姆普丁克的婚礼
If you heal him, he will stop Humperdinck's wedding.
闭嘴！等等
Shut up! Wait a minute.
我治好他 胡姆普丁克就会受罪？
I make him better, Humperdinck suffers?
狠狠的羞辱！
Humiliations galore!
这是高尚的理由
That is a noble cause.
把65元给我.我来工作
Give me the sixty-five. I'm on the job.
那就是奇迹药了？
That's a miracle pill?
巧克力糖衣 会容易吞服点…
The chocolate coating makes it go down easier...
但你得等15分钟 他的力量才会完全恢复…
but you have to wait 15 minutes for full potency...
而你至少不能游，什么？
and you shouldn't go swimming for at least, what?
-一个小时的泳 -对，一个小时
- An hour. A good hour. - Yeah, an hour.
非常感谢
Thank you for everything.
再见了，伙计
Bye-bye, boys.
愉快地袭击古堡吧
Have fun storming the castle.
认为这有用吗？
Think it'll work?
这会产生一个奇迹
It would take a miracle.
有什么情况？
Anything?
埃尼戈，不止30人
Inigo, there's more than thirty.
有什么区别？
What's the difference?
我们有他
We've got him.
帮我一把
Help me here.
我们得喂他吃
We'll have to force-feed him.
有没15分钟了？
Has it been fifteen minutes?
我们不能等了. 婚礼半小时后就会举行了
We can't wait. The wedding's in half an hour.
我们得急急忙忙地攻击
We must strike in the hustle and bustle beforehand.
扶正他的头
Tilt his head back.
张开他的嘴
Open his mouth.
在我们知道奇迹 是否有效时…
How long do we have to wait...
我们还要等多久？
before if we know the miracle works?
你的猜测和我的一样棒
Your guess is as good as mine.
我会把你打得稀巴烂！ 我会处理你们俩！
I'll beat you apart! I'll take you both together!
我猜不会太久了
I guess not very long.
我的手臂怎么动不了？
Why won't my arms move?
你几乎要死了
You've been mostly dead all day.
我们让马克斯奇迹酿制了 一粒药才让你苏醒过来的
We had Miracle Max make a pill to bring you back.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我们是对手吗？
Are we enemies?
我怎么会在这围墙里的？
Why am I on this wall?
布特卡普在哪儿？
Where's Buttercup?
让我来解释
Let me explain.
不，太多了. 我们长话短说吧
No, there is too much. Let me sum up.
布特卡普在半小时后就要 和胡姆普丁克结婚了…
Buttercup's marrying Humperdinck in less than half an hour...
所以我们要做的就是闯进去 阻止这个婚礼…
so all we have to do is get in, break up the wedding...
抢了公主，然后就跑….
steal the princess, make our escape...
当然我还把雷根杀了
after I kill Count Rugen.
没时间耽搁了
That doesn't leave much time for dilly-dallying.
你刚才摆动了你的手指！
You just wiggled your finger!
太好了！
That's wonderful!
我向来康复都挺快的
I've always been a quick healer.
我们干怎样做？
What are our liabilities?
古堡只有一扇大门
There is but one working castle gate.
来
Come on.
有60个人把守
And it is guarded by sixty men.
我们有什么武器？
And our assets?
你的头脑 菲兹克的力量，我的剑
Your brains, Fezzik's strength, my steel.
就这些？
That's it?
不可能
Lmpossible.
如果我有一个月 的时间计划…
If I had a month to plan...
或许我会找到什么好主意 但这个…
maybe I could come up with something, but this...
你刚才动了你的头！
You just shook your head!
那不会让你高兴吧？
That doesn't make you happy?
我的头脑，他的剑…
My brains, his steel...
你抵挡60人的力量…
and your strength against sixty men...
轻微的头部摇动 会让我高兴吗？
and a little head jiggle is supposed to make me happy?
如果我们有手推车 那又不同
If we only had a wheelbarrow, that would be something.
怎样用那手推车？
Where did we put the wheelbarrow the albino had?
摆一个巨人上面，我想
Over the albino, I think.
你怎么就不把这个当作 是我们的武器而放在第一位呢？
Why didn't you list that among our assets in the first place?
如果我有斗篷就好了
What I wouldn't give for a holocaust cloak.
那我们就帮不了你了
There we cannot help you.
这个行吗？
Will this do?
-哪里拿的？ -马克斯奇迹家里
- Where did you get that? - At Miracle Max's.
这很适合我 他说可以给我
It fit so nice, he said I could keep it.
好的.来吧，扶我起来
All right. Come on, help me up.
我最需要的是一把剑
I'll need a sword eventually.
为什么？你可拿不起咧
Why? You can't even lift one.
真的，但这可是常识，对吧？
True, but that's hardly common knowledge, is it?
谢谢
Thank you.
我们进去后，或许有问题
There may be problems once we're inside.
我是说. 我怎样才能找到伯爵？
I'll say. How do I find the count?
如果我找到了 我怎样才能找回你们？
Once I do, how do I find you again?
找到你们后，我们又怎样逃跑？
Once I find you again, how do we escape?
别烦他
Don't pester him.
他心情不好
He's had a hard day.
对，对.不好意思
Right, right. Sorry.
-埃尼戈 -什么？
- Inigo. - What?
我希望我们会赢
I hope we win.
你似乎不是很兴奋 我的伙计
You don't seem excited, my little muffin.
我该兴奋吗？
Should I be?
新娘的样子了
Brides often are, I'm told.
我今晚不结婚
I do not marry tonight.
我的维斯特雷会来救我的
My Westley will save me.
婚姻…
Marriage...
婚姻使我们今天相聚一起
Marriage is what brings us together... today.
婚姻…
Marriage...
是一个受祝福的典礼…
that blessed arrangement...
是一个梦想中的梦想…
that dream within a dream...
坚守阵地啊！
Stand your ground, men!
我是可怕的海盗罗伯茨
I am the Dread Pirate Roberts.
这里不会有人活着离开
There will be no survivor!
-现在？ -还不是
- Now? - Not yet.
我的人马到了
My men are here.
我也到了…
I am here...
但很快你们就不在了
but soon you will not be here.
-现在？ -点火
- Now? - Light him.
可怕的海盗罗伯茨…
The Dread Pirate Roberts...
不会放过任何人
takes no survivors.
你们所有的恶梦…
All your worst nightmares...
都要成真了
are about to come true.
那么爱…
Then love...
真爱…
true love...
会永远…
will follow you...
跟随你们
forever.
可怕的海盗罗伯茨…
The Dread Pirate Roberts...
来要你的灵魂了！
is here for your souls!
坚守住啊！
Stay where you are!
开战！
Fight!
坚守啊！
Stay where you are!
所以珍惜你们的爱
So treasure your love.
跳到最后
Skip to the end.
你有戒指吗？
Have you the ring?
我的维斯特雷来了
Here comes my Westley now.
菲兹克，铁闸门！
Fezzik, the portcullis!
你的维斯特雷死了！
Your Westley is dead.
我亲手杀死他了
I killed him myself.
那你为什么眼神里 透露着惧怕？
Then why is there fear behind your eyes?
把大门钥匙给我
Give us the gate key.
我没有大门钥匙
I have no gate key.
菲兹克 把他的手臂给撕下来
Fezzik, tear his arms off.
你是说这扇门的钥匙吧？
You mean this gate key?
你呢，布特卡普公主…
...and do you, Princess Buttercup...
丈夫和妻子！ 说丈夫和妻子！
Man and wife! Say man and wife!
丈夫和妻子
Man and wife.
带新娘回新房
Escort the bride to the honeymoon suite.
我很快就到
I'll be there shortly.
他没来
He didn't come.
把那黑衣的 和巨人给杀了…
Kill the dark one and the giant...
留着第三个人来审问
but leave the third for questioning.
我叫埃尼戈.蒙托亚
My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
准备等死吧
Prepare to die.
我需要你
I need you!
我不能撇开他啊
I can't leave him alone.
他逃远了，菲兹克
He's getting away from me, Fezzik!
拜托
Please!
我就回来
I'll be right back.
谢谢
Thank you.
奇怪的婚礼
Strange wedding.
对，一个非常奇怪的婚礼
Yes... a very strange wedding.
来
Come along.
为什么？
What was that for?
因为你一直都对我很好
Because you've always been so kind to me.
而我不会再见到你了…
And I won't be seeing you again...
我回到新房后就要自杀了
since I'm killing myself once we reach the honeymoon suite.
那会更好吗？
Won't that be nice?
她吻我了！
She kissed me!
对不起，父亲
Sorry, Father.
我试过了
I tried.
你就肯定是多年前…
You must be that little Spanish brat...
教训过的那西班牙小子
I taught a lesson to all those years ago.
真不可思议
Simply incredible.
你一直以来都在追捕我…
Have you been chasing me your whole life...
而结果又是失败啊？
only to fail now?
我想这是我听 说过的最难过的事情
I think that's the worst thing I've ever heard.
真是令人惊讶
How marvelous.
世界上就是缺乏一种胸怀
There's a shortage of perfect breasts in this world.
破坏了你的真可惜
It would be a pity to damage yours.
噢，维斯特雷，亲爱的
Oh, Westley, darling!
维斯特雷 你为什么不抱我啊？
Westley, why won't you hold me?
温柔地
Gently.
特别是像这样的时刻…
At a time like this...
这就是你所能想出要说的 温柔地？
that's all you can think to say, gently?
温柔地！
Gently!
天啊，你还想赢啊？
Good heavens, are you still trying to win?
你的复仇欲望 真是过于强烈了
You've got an overdeveloped sense of vengeance.
某天这会让你遇上r烦的
It's going to get you into trouble someday.
我叫埃尼戈.蒙托亚
My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
准备等死吧
Prepare to die.
我叫埃尼戈.蒙托亚
My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father.
准备等死吧
Prepare to die.
你好！我叫埃尼戈.蒙托亚
Hello! My name is Inigo Montoya.
你杀了我的父亲. 准备等死吧
You killed my father. Prepare to die.
别再说了！
Stop saying that!
你好！我叫埃尼戈.蒙托亚
Hello! My name is Inigo Montoya!
你杀了我的父亲
You killed my father!
准备等死吧
Prepare to die!
给我出个价
Offer me money.
权力也可以，保证有
Power, too, promise me that.
我的一切
All that I have and more, please.
我所要的一切，出个价吧
Offer me everything I ask for.
你所要的一切
Anything you want.
我要的是我的父亲 你这个狗杂种！
I want my father back, you son of a bitch!
维斯特雷，你能原谅我吗？
Westley, will you ever forgive me?
你最近又犯了什么 可怕的错误了？
What hideous sin have you committed lately?
我结婚了.我并不想 但发生得很快
I got married. I didn't want to. It all happened so fast.
不会再发生了. 不会再发生了
It never happened. It never happened.
但是发生.我就在那儿
But it did. I was there.
那老人说丈夫和妻子
This old man said man and wife.
你有没说我愿意？
Did you say I do?
我们是跳到那一部分的
We sort of skipped that part.
那么你就还没成婚嘛
Then you're not married.
如果你没说，你就没做
If you didn't say it, you didn't do it.
你难道不同意吗，殿下？
Wouldn't you agree, Your Highness?
学术的东西很快就会被修补
A technicality that will shortly be remedied.
但首先
But first things first.
为了死亡
To the death.
为了痛苦
To the pain.
我认为我不是 很熟悉这样的句子
I don't think I'm quite familiar with that phrase.
我来解释…
I'll explain...
我说得具体点 这样你就肯定会明白了…
and I'll use small words so that you'll be sure to understand...
你这个悲怜的小丑
you warthog-faced buffoon.
这是我一生中第一次…
That may be the first time in my life...
有人敢侮辱我
a man has dared insult me.
这不会是最后一次
It won't be the last.
为了痛苦的意思是 你首先要失去的是…
To the pain means the first thing you lose...
你踝下之脚
will be your feet below the ankles...
然后是你腕上之手…
then your hands at the wrists...
接着就是你的鼻子
next your nose.
我想，然后就是我的舌头
And then my tongue, I suppose.
我上次杀你杀得太快了
I killed you too quickly the last time...
我今晚不能 重复同样的错误了
a mistake I don't mean to duplicate tonight.
我还没说完
I wasn't finished.
接下来你失去的是你的左眼 然后到你的右眼
The next thing you lose will be your left eye, then your right.
而后就是我的耳朵. 我明白！我们来吧！
And then my ears. I understand! Let's get on with it!
错！你会保留你的耳朵 让我告诉你为什么…
Wrong! Your ears you keep, and I'll tell you why...
这样每个小孩一看到你这样的 怪物时都会发出尖叫声…
so every shriek of every child at seeing your hideousness...
这个你就可以珍藏着
will be yours to cherish.
每个婴儿一看到 你靠近就会哭…
Every babe that weeps at your approach...
每个女人都会大叫 “天啊，这是什么东西啊…”
every woman who cries out, ''God, what is that thing''...
这些都会回荡在 你完整无缺的耳边
will echo in your perfect ears.
那就是“为了痛苦”的含意
That is what ''to the pain'' means.
这意味着让你痛苦…
It means I leave you in anguish...
永远徘徊于怪物的痛苦里
wallowing in freakish misery forever.
我想你是在吹牛
I think you're bluffing.
这是完全可能的，蠢蛋！
It's possible, pig!
我或许是吹牛
I might be bluffing.
这是可以想像的 你这个令人作呕的小丑…
It's conceivable, you miserable vomitous mass...
我只是会在这儿撒谎 因为我连站起来的力气都没有
I'm only lying here because I lack the strength to stand.
又来了…
Then again...
或者我有力气呢
perhaps I have the strength after all.
放下剑
Drop your sword.
坐下
Have a seat.
把他绑起来
Tie him up.
尽量绑紧点
Make it as tight as you like.
菲兹克在哪儿？
Where's Fezzik?
我以为他和你在一起
I thought he was with you.
这样的话…
In that case...
去帮他
Help him.
为什么维斯特雷需要帮助？
Why does Westley need helping?
因为他没力气了
Because he has no strength.
我就知道你是在吹牛！
I knew you were bluffing! I knew he was bluffing.
-要不要给你了结他？ -谢谢，但不用
- Shall I dispatch him for you? - Thank you, but no.
无论我们发生什么…
Whatever happens to us...
我要他活着 带着他的懦弱活着
I want him to live a long life, alone with his cowardice.
埃尼戈，你在哪儿？
Inigo, where are you?
你在这儿啊
There you are.
埃尼戈，我看到王子的马房
Inigo, I saw the prince's stables...
看，有四匹白马
and there they were, four white horses.
我想，我们有四个人…
And I thought, there are four of us...
如果我们找到那女士的话
if we ever find the lady.
你好，女士
Hello, lady.
所以我就带上了 这样我们就不用挤了
So I took them with me in case we ever bumped into each other.
我想我们刚成功了
I guess we just did.
你做得很好
You did something right.
别东西，我不会飘飘然的
Don't worry. I won't let it go to my head.
你知道…
You know...
这很奇怪
it's very strange.
我一直都是为了复仇…
I have been in the revenge business so long...
现在结束了…
now that it's over...
我真不知道我接下来的 生活中要干些什么
I don't know what to do with the rest of my life.
有没考虑过当海盗？
Have you ever considered piracy?
你会是一位出色的 可怕的海盗罗伯茨的
You'd make a wonderful Dread Pirate Roberts.
他们奔向自由
They rode to freedom.
黎明时分，维斯特雷和布特卡普 知道他们已经安全了
And as dawn arose, Westley and Buttercup knew they were safe.
爱的波浪涌入他们
A wave of love swept over them.
他们就在一起了…
And as they reached for each other...
什么？什么？
What? What?
又接吻了.你不会想听的
It's kissing again. You don't want to hear that.
我也不会太在意了
I don't mind so much.
自从发明接吻…
Since the invention of the kiss...
有五种吻是…
there have been five kisses...
最充满热情的…
that were rated the most passionate...
最纯洁的
the most pure.
而这一个吻让它们望尘莫及
This one left them all behind.
结束
The end.
现在，我想你该睡觉了
Now I think you ought to go to sleep.
好的
All right.
再见
So long.
爷爷…
Grandpa...
或许明天你也过来…
maybe you could come over...
再给我念念
and read it again to me tomorrow.
遵你所愿
As you wish.